<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<article>
  <title>Firefly Media Server Manual</title>

  <section>
    <title>Overview</title>

    <para>The Firefly Media Server is an open-source media server for the Roku
    SoundBridge and iTunes. Generally, it supports the following
    features:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Integrates with iTunes, reading playlists even when iTunes is
        not running</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Runs in the background, without requiring user login
        (unix/windows)</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>System tray (Windows)/Preference Pane (ouMac) allows for quick
        and easy configuration</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Web-based interface allows for more advanced
        configuration</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Support transcoding of many audio formats, including AAC, ALAC,
        WMA, FLAC, and Ogg/Vorbis. (Supported formats vary by platform)</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Cross platform, running on Windows, Mac, and Linux</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Actively developed</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>Full details of configuring and installing Firefly to take advantage
    of these features are detailed below.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Installation</title>

    <para>Firefly Media Server can be downloaded from the project web site at
    <uri>http://www.fireflymediaserver.org</uri>. This manual describes the
    current stable version: svn-1359.</para>

    <para>If you anticipate using a Roku SoundBridge as a client to the
    Firefly Media Server, please consider upgrading the Roku firmware to
    version 2.5.173 or later. To check your software version and to upgrade,
    use your SoundBridge remote to go to Change Library or
    Configuration-&gt;System Configuration-&gt;Software Version and Updates.
    Follow the on screen instructions to check for newer software and to
    upgrade.</para>

    <para>Details of installing the Firefly Media Server vary by platform.
    Please read the detailed installation instructions for the platform you
    use.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Windows Installation</title>

      <para>The Firefly Media Server will run on Windows 2000 or Window XP
      workstations. Please follow the steps below to install the Firefly Media
      Server.</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Download and install Apple's Bonjour for Windows. At the time
          of this writing, this can be found at the following location:
          <uri>http://www.apple.com/support/downloads/bonjourforwindows103.html.</uri></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>If you wish to transcode WMA files, including WMA Lossless,
          please download and install Microsoft's Windows Media Player 10 or
          later.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Download and install svn-1359 from the Firefly Media Server
          site at <uri>http://www.fireflymediaserver.org</uri></para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <para>After following the directions in the installer, the Firefly
      server should start automatically and being indexing music files. Once
      the files are indexed (at approximately 5000 songs per minute), the
      Firefly server should appear in iTunes or the Roku SoundBridge. If it
      does not, please refer to the troubleshooting section.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Mac Installation</title>

      <para>The instructions for the Mac installation are contained in the
      README file in the Mac disk image.</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Download the current Mac disk image from
          <uri>http://www.fireflymediaserver.org</uri></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Mount the .dmg file by double-clicking on it</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Follow the instructions in the README file</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <para>Once installed, use the Preference Pane just installed to start
      the Firefly Server. The initial startup will take some time, as the
      server must index all existing songs. One the server has finished
      indexing the files, it should appear in iTunes, or in the Roku
      SoundBridge library browser. If it does not, please refer to the
      troubleshooting section.</para>

      <para></para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Configuration</title>

    <para>There are generally three ways to configure the Firefly Media
    Server: Using the tray applet/prefs panel on Windows and Mac, by editing
    the configuration file directly, or by using the web-based configuration
    interface.</para>

    <section>
      <title>General</title>

      <para></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Windows Tray Applet</title>

      <para></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Mac Preference Panel</title>

      <para></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Config File Editing</title>

      <para></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Web Interface Configuration</title>

      <para></para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Resources</title>

    <para></para>

    <section>
      <title>Playlists</title>

      <para></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>XML-RPC Guide</title>

      <para></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Troubleshooting</title>

      <para></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>FAQ</title>

      <para></para>
    </section>
  </section>
</article>